hi my name is Joe Brewer and I'm the
director of cognitive policy works and
i'm here to share with you a project
that we've decided to initiate in
partnership with darwin SF to help get
the global culture to a tipping point or
we can finally tackle climate change now
for those of you who don't know me 10
years ago i was studying atmospheric
science in graduate school and i
realized that the biggest problem
stalling out action on this huge huge
issue was large-scale human behavior the
social norms and values of society the
way that we construct incentives and our
institutions so I left atmospheric
science and I moved into the cognitive
and behavioral sciences and now a decade
later I have been applying these skills
and knowledge to a whole host of
problems and challenges in the social
advocacy and innovation space and now I
finally feel prepared to tackle what I
initially set forth to learn these
things for which is to address climate
change now if like me you've been
watching with a growing sense of unease
fear frustration that the looming
threats of climate change and global
warming just keep getting more and more
pervasive we have you know floods and
droughts extreme weather like hurricane
sandy bearing down on New York City
earlier this month and still even in
spite of that the massive PR campaign
that spread confusion and doubt about
climate change remains effective and
there's a leadership vacuum in the world
so what we're doing in this project is
worth sidestepping all of the broken
institutions that have gotten in the way
and going directly to the crowd and our
goal is to gather all of the memes
meaning all of the ideas out there alive
and culture that help climate action and
those that hinder climate action and we
want to create a map of those different
ideas so that we can see how they all
relate to each other and then use that
information to help convey to climate
activists how they can create a movement
that actually gets us to a cultural
tipping point
and that's what we need your help with
here today